finally let us discuss in our OB based
out of order execution processor what
really is out of order here so this is a
processor pipeline let's say this is the
fetch stage there is a decode stage we
issue then we dispatch and then we have
execution and then the write of the
result which is the broadcast we have
and then finally the commit so in this
pipeline if this was an out of order
processor keep in mind that not all of
these stages are processing instructions
out of order
in fact from fetch up to issue we are
processing instructions in order we have
to fetch them in the order that they
should appear in the program within
decode them in the correct order and we
fetch them if you remember in order this
ensures that any dependencies we figure
out here are the dependencies that are
compatible with the original program
order now that we have issued
instructions to reservation stations and
they're waiting for execution they're
gonna execute in the order of data
dependencies not necessarily in program
order so the execution and writing of
results are happening out of order and
then again commit needs to do
instructions in the proper program order
because if you remember the order of
committing is really the order in which
we tell the outside world that we are
finishing instructions so this has to
happen in order to give the appearance
that we are executing instructions in
program order so when we have an out of
order processor it really is doing many
stages in order and only the execution
and broadcast and things in between are
happening out of order so the
dispatching the execution the writing of
results everything else is still in
order in contrast what we would call an
inorder processor just as these in order
to but even an out of order processor
does a lot of things in order